<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Film | Four-Point Play]]></title>
  <link href="http://four-point-play.herokuapp.com/blog/categories/film/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://four-point-play.herokuapp.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-03-13T23:22:44-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://four-point-play.herokuapp.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Logesh and Geoff]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Academy Awards Preview]]></title>
    <link href="http://four-point-play.herokuapp.com/blog/2015/02/21/academy-awards-preview/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-21T07:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://four-point-play.herokuapp.com/blog/2015/02/21/academy-awards-preview</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My prognostications for the major Academy Awards.</p>

<p><img src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-ag3cbBzudsM/VLvfgGWe7uI/AAAAAAAASig/MnXRsLeh-m4/s1600/J.K.%2BSimmons%2BWhiplash.PNG" title="Not quite my tempo" alt="alt text" /></p>

<!--more-->


<h2>Best Supporting Actor</h2>

<p>Nominees &ndash; Robert Duvall (<em>The Judge</em>), Ethan Hawke (<em>Boyhood</em>), Edward Norton (<em>Birdman</em>), Mark Ruffalo (<em>Foxcatcher</em>), J.K. Simmons (<em>Whiplash</em>)</p>

<p>Should win &ndash; <strong>J.K. Simmons</strong></p>

<p>Will win &ndash; <strong>J.K. Simmons</strong></p>

<p>Not having seen this film until after my Oscars post, I am in elation that it is up for a few awards and receiving recognition. So many positives to talk about &ndash; evocative editing, a tight screenplay, and Miles Teller&rsquo;s stupendous drumming skills. And, of course, J.K. Simmons is chilling as the abusive conservatory conductor that cruelly manipulates his disciple. Oh, remember how in the beginning Miles Teller&rsquo;s character asks out the movie theater clerk&hellip; I&rsquo;ve always wanted to do that.</p>

<hr />

<p><img src="http://media1.onsugar.com/files/2014/07/02/018/n/1922283/53ec746af1a7bba0_pat2.xxxlarge.jpg" title="Awwwww" alt="alt text" /></p>

<h2>Best Supporting Actress</h2>

<p>Nominees &ndash; Patricia Arquette (Boyhood), Laura Dern (Wild), Keira Knightley (The Imitation Game), Emma Stone (Birdman), Meryl Streep (Into The Woods)</p>

<p>Should win &ndash; <strong>Patricia Arquette</strong></p>

<p>Will win &ndash; <strong>Patricia Arquette</strong></p>

<p>I haven&rsquo;t seen most of the films in this category, but Arquette has won the SAG, BAFTA (UK Oscars), and GG. Her performance culminates in a speech to Mason as he packs for college &ndash; she thought there would be more. It is so heartwrenching after witnessing all her tribulations with abusive husbands to see a mom want more time with her son. Or think that the time would have meant something more. I remember my mom feeling the same way when I went off to college, and I&rsquo;m sure the feeling of separation is univeral among <a href="http://www.hiphopearly.com/Drake-You-The-6-t27119.html">all moms</a>.</p>

<hr />

<p><img src="http://cdn.collider.com/wp-content/uploads/inherent-vice-image-joaquin-phoenix-katherine-waterston-joanna-newsom.jpg" title="Ouija!" alt="alt text" /></p>

<h2>Best Adapted Screenplay</h2>

<p>Nominees &ndash; <em>American Sniper</em>, <em>The Imitation Game</em>, <em>Inherent Vice</em>, <em>The Theory of Everything</em>, <em>Whiplash</em></p>

<p>Should win &ndash; <strong><em>Inherent Vice</em></strong></p>

<p>Will win &ndash; <strong><em>The Imitation Game</em></strong></p>

<p>What I&rsquo;ve been hearing on the interwebs is that the Weinstein company has been pushing hard for <em>The Imitation Game</em> to at least win this category. As Harvey Weinstein desires, it shall be. But, adapting Thomas Pynchon&rsquo;s schizophrenic novel for the screen is no easy task. The work that P.T. Anderson and Pynchon put in to make <em>Inherent Vice&rsquo;s</em> narrative evoke the themes and style of the book is worthy of an Oscar here.</p>

<hr />

<p><img src="https://cdn2.thedissolve.com/features/464/fullwidth.e4b3e81c.JPG" title="Agatha &amp; Zero" alt="alt text" /></p>

<h2>Best Original Screenplay</h2>

<p>Nominees &ndash; <em>Birdman</em>, <em>Boyhood</em>, <em>Foxcatcher</em>, <em>The Grand Budapest Hotel</em>, <em>Nightcrawler</em></p>

<p>Should win &ndash; <strong><em>The Grand Budapest Hotel</em></strong></p>

<p>Will win &ndash; <strong><em>The Grand Budapest Hotel</em></strong></p>

<p>If you don&rsquo;t remember, <em>The Grand Budapest Hotel&rsquo;s</em> narrative structure is as follows &ndash; a young woman visits the grave of a famous author who wrote a story called <em>The Grand Budapest Hotel</em>, we cut to the author reminiscing about the story, we flashback again to when the younger author met an older Zero Moustafa who told him the story, and then we go back once more to the time that the events were taking place. This is no easy feat.  Not to mention the precise dialogue and mannerisms of M. Gustave and the supporting cast. I love this movie <a href="https://vimeo.com/119754714">(and so does this guy)</a>. Wes Anderson deserves this award in spades.</p>

<hr />

<p><img src="http://www.northcoastjournal.com/imager/b/original/2489631/c58a/Filmland.jpg" title="Boo - fuck you Batman" alt="alt text" /></p>

<h2>Best Animated Film</h2>

<p>Nominees &ndash; <em>Big Hero 6</em>, <em>The Boxtrolls</em>, <em>How To Train Your Dragon 2</em>, <em>Song Of The Sea</em>, <em>The Tale Of The Princess Kaguya</em></p>

<p>Should win &ndash; <strong><em>The Lego Movie</em></strong> (not nominated)</p>

<p>Will win &ndash; <strong><em>How To Train Your Dragon 2</em></strong></p>

<p><em>The Lego Movie</em> was robbed of a nomination here. No matter, it lends some purity to its legacy. One of the directors, Phil Lord, had the <a href="https://twitter.com/philiplord/status/555729488164569089">perfect response</a>.</p>

<hr />

<p><img src="http://cdn.theatlantic.com/assets/media/img/posts/2015/02/Theory_of_Everything/8ef785ca3.jpg" title="Who?" alt="alt text" /></p>

<h2>Best Actor</h2>

<p>Nominees &ndash; Steve Carell (<em>Foxcatcher</em>), Bradley Cooper (<em>American Sniper</em>), Benedictus Cumbersnoot (<em>The Imitation Game</em>), Michael Keaton (<em>Birdman</em>), Eddie Redmayne (<em>The Theory of Everything</em>)</p>

<p>Should win &ndash; <strong>Ralph Fiennes</strong> (<em>The Grand Budapest Hotel</em>), <strong>Jake Gyllenhaal</strong> (<em>Nightcrawler</em>), <strong>Oscar Isaac</strong> (<em>A Most Violent Year</em>), or <strong>David Oyelowo</strong> (<em>Selma</em>) (None nominated)</p>

<p>Will win &ndash; <strong>Eddie Redmayne</strong></p>

<p>The Academy loves gimmicks &ndash; Tom Hanks for <em>Forrest Gump</em>, Dustin Hoffman for <em>Rain Man</em>. The Academy also loves rewarding people with what represents a lifetime achievement award for a more current release &ndash; Scorcese for <em>The Departed</em>. Eddie Redmayne has been on a roll, picking up awards for essentially playing a disease process (ALS). Michael Keaton is the most deserving in this category because it was an Oscar-worthy performance, he has been neglected by the Academy for a long time, and he was fucking Batman.</p>

<hr />

<p><img src="http://moviemezzanine.com/wp-content/uploads/GONE-GIRL-Movie-HD-Trailer-Captures00004_1_11.jpg" title="So scary" alt="alt text" /></p>

<h2>Best Actress</h2>

<p>Nominees &ndash; Marion Cotillard (<em>Two Days, One Night</em>), Felicity Jones (<em>The Theory Of Everything</em>), Julianne Moore (<em>Still Alice</em>), Rosamund Pike (<em>Gone Girl</em>), Reese Witherspoon (<em>Wild</em>)</p>

<p>Should win &ndash; <strong>Rosamund Pike</strong> (actually <strong>Scarlett Johansson</strong> if she was nominated for <em>Under The Skin</em>)</p>

<p>Will win &ndash; <strong>Julianne Moore</strong></p>

<p>I haven&rsquo;t seen <em>Still Alice</em>, but Julianne Moore is excellent in everything she&rsquo;s in, and she has won all the awards for this category, so it&rsquo;s going to her. Thing is, she is also playing a disease process here (Alzheimer&rsquo;s). I would much rather give this to Rosamund Pike whose performance centered <em>Gone Girl</em>. She captured the psychological intricacies of the character in every moment. She is really the remaining image in my mind when I think of <em>Gone Girl</em>. That and Ben Affleck&rsquo;s penis.</p>

<hr />

<p><img src="http://d1oi7t5trwfj5d.cloudfront.net/a1/1a03f0946511e1bcc4123138165f92/file/the-films-of-richard-linklater-a-retrospective.jpg" title="This guy" alt="alt text" /></p>

<h2>Best Director</h2>

<p>Nominees &ndash; Alejandro González Iñárritu (Birdman), Richard Linklater (Boyhood), Bennett Miller (Foxcatcher), Wes Anderson (The Grand Budapest Hotel), Morten Tyldum (The Imitation Game)</p>

<p>Who should win &ndash; <strong>Ava DuVernay</strong> for <em>Selma</em> (not nominated)</p>

<p>Who will win &ndash; <strong>Richard Linkater</strong></p>

<p>I went to a Q &amp; A with Richard Linklater when I was up in NYC. It was so cool! He&rsquo;s just as jovial and insightful in real life as I hoped he would be! Too bad my question was passed up for some other assholes at Apple SoHo who wouldn&rsquo;t know how to address a brick, much less a legendary director. Yeesh. Anyway, Iñárritu is the other favorite in this category, and he won the DGA, while Linklater won all the other awards. I hope the voters don&rsquo;t deny the vision and patience of the 12-year spectacle that is <em>Boyhood</em>.</p>

<hr />

<p><img src="http://www.selmamovie.com/images/photos/10.jpg" title="MLK" alt="alt text" /></p>

<h2>Best Picture</h2>

<p>Nominees &ndash; <em>American Sniper</em>, <em>Birdman</em>, <em>Boyhood</em>, <em>The Grand Budapest Hotel</em>, <em>The Imitation Game</em>, <em>Selma</em>, <em>The Theory Of Everything</em>, <em>Whiplash</em></p>

<p>Should win &ndash; <strong><em>Selma</em></strong></p>

<p>Will win &ndash; <strong><em>Boyhood</em></strong></p>

<p>All the Best Picture nominees this year are about white males, directed by white males, except one. <em>Selma</em>, directed by an African-American female, Ava DuVernay, only has 2 nominations at the Oscars this year as a result of the movie finishing late, and the screeners not getting to voters in time for the guild awards, preventing it from gaining any momentum on the awards circuit. Oh and it is also <a href="http://grantland.com/features/selma-oscars-academy-awards-historical-accuracy-controversy/">being smeared</a> by anti-intellectuals for its portrayal of Lyndon B. Johnson.  The tone-deaf inanity of some people is infuriating.</p>

<p>The film is about the voting rights marches from Selma to Montegomery in 1965 led by MLK. It dives into the politics, strategy and practicality of the movement and it is never boring. The directing, dialogue, and cinematography is on point and David Oyelowo as MLK is on another level. On top of all that, it is the most important movie of last year in the wake of all the violence perpetrated against black people. There is a depressing irony of a movie about MLK being criticized of its portrayal of a white person. <em>Selma</em> was riveting, go watch it.</p>

<p>-I.I.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Top 10 Films of 2014]]></title>
    <link href="http://four-point-play.herokuapp.com/blog/2015/01/01/top-10-films-of-2014/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-01T18:59:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://four-point-play.herokuapp.com/blog/2015/01/01/top-10-films-of-2014</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My ranking of the best 10 movies that came out last year. And a little bit about them.</p>

<p><img src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-g1tCfxUzCQk/VFsGJeJPGWI/AAAAAAAABOQ/Mki712aPUcI/s1600/6vFcgup.jpg" /></p>

<!--more-->


<p>Not seen yet: Whiplash, Inherent Vice, Selma</p>

<h3>10 &ndash; Nightcrawler</h3>

<p>Lou Bloom (Jake Gyllenhaal) reminds me of the many creeps I have come across in my life. He is a representation of the worst part of modern capitalism and what it breeds. <em>Nightcrawler</em> is the story of a hyperverbal, self-made, meticulous student of psychology who applies it to the world of L.A. crime journalism. Bloom&rsquo;s brilliance at manipulating his surroundings is mesmerizing. And his fierce dedication is both unnerving and enviable. We can only imagine where he will be in 20 years, <em>or</em> where today&rsquo;s CEOs were 20 years ago.</p>

<h3>9 &ndash; Snowpiercer</h3>

<p>Chris Evans, aka Captain America, stars in Joon-ho Bong&rsquo;s thriller, which takes place on a pyschedelic train circling a post-apocalyptic ice Earth. C'mon. You should probably go see it even if you don&rsquo;t care about the subtext I am about to explain. We tend to believe that our governing bodies are structured to make decisions for the &ldquo;greater good&rdquo;.  But when people are dissatisfied <strong>and</strong> think <em>they</em> know what is better for everyone, a revolution is born. But are all revolutionaries doomed to implement an essentially identical hierarchical system? In Egypt, Mubarak was ousted in a twitter-famous coup in 2011. In a matter of 2 years, his replacement Morsi, who got greedy with power, was also overthrown. Joon-ho Bong takes no issue with laying bare for his viewers the psychological brutality of revolution.</p>

<h3>8 &ndash; Interstellar</h3>

<p>Many great directors need to tackle their space-epic movie. Kubrick and <em>2001: A Space Odyssey</em>. Joss Whedon and <em>Serenity</em>. And Alfonso Cuaron&rsquo;s <em>Gravity</em>. Chris Nolan has held his weight with his entry into this tradition. First of all, it is a treat for people who love to untangle the complicated plotlines that movie&rsquo;s with time travel inevitably provide. It takes a considerable amount of mental energy to put all the pieces of this movie together, but it is so, so satisfying. As a bonus, this is a situation that you might actually learn things if you pay attention because Nolan spent an exhaustive amount of time discussing the science with actual physicists. The obligatory star-studded cast of actors in a Nolan movie is at the top of their game. Not to mention the awesome comedic relief robot sidekicks. And don&rsquo;t forget the brilliant visuals of space, wormholes, and Alberta, Canada. Sure it gets a little too sweet at the end, as Nolan is apt to do, but I think this time it was well-earned.</p>

<h3>7 &ndash; Edge Of Tomorrow</h3>

<p><em>Edge Of Tomorrow</em> features a criminally underrated performance by Tom  Cruise in the sci-fi Groundhog Day. The psychological effects of reliving a day endlessly are so fun to ponder. This film takes that idea very seriously and makes sure you feel deeply the frustration of repeatedly failing at figuring out how to &ldquo;win the day.&rdquo; This is all occurring in the middle of a futuristic war against a time-bending alien. For all the action films he&rsquo;s been in, you have never wanted Tom Cruise not-to-die more, than in this one.</p>

<h3>6 &ndash; The One I Love</h3>

<p>In my social circles, there have been a bevy of engagements. This has given me a lot of food for thought regarding what marriage means, why that is important, and oh-god-I&rsquo;m-going-to-die-alone. Mark Duplass (<em>The League</em>) and Elisabeth Moss (<em>Mad Men</em>) play a couple whose marriage is on the rocks and try to save it with a weekend getaway in a mysterious house. Once there, we are treated to one of the most fun sci-fi setups in a year filled with great sci-fi movies. It allows some of the questions of marriage to play out. What would you do to recapture that initial magic? What is it about a person that actually makes you want to stay? Moss and Duplass get into the messy, embarrassing, and immensely relatable feelings that we all have regarding the people close to us, and the expectations we stupidly place on them.</p>

<h3>5 &ndash; The LEGO Movie</h3>

<p>Movies are so ingrained in our psyche that we sometimes see ourselves as the star of our own life. Everyone else are just the extras. Phil Lord &amp; Chris Miller just go ahead and call it like it is; we all want to be the &ldquo;Special&rdquo; i.e. &ldquo;the most special, most talented, and most extraordinary person in the universe&rdquo;. Emmet (Chris Pratt) is thrown into a situation where this wish comes true, and everyone thinks he is the &ldquo;Special&rdquo;, who will save them all. But this movie is the anti-<em>Guardians of the Galaxy</em>. In LEGO-land (sorry) blood tests don&rsquo;t reveal that we are actually unique at the end of the day. I, like Emmet, feel stupid compared to other people, am constantly encountering girls who already have a boyfriend, and would do almost anything for my friends. This movie resonates so well because it validates those everyday feelings. I haven&rsquo;t even mentioned that the twist belongs in the top 10 of all time, that it has a spot-on deconstruction of <a href="http://youtu.be/StTqXEQ2l-Y">modern pop music</a>, and a beautiful blend of CGI/stop-motion animation.</p>

<p><img src="http://cinemagogue.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/yGlBbZb.jpg"></p>

<h3>4 &ndash; Gone Girl</h3>

<p>I&rsquo;m going to do away with withholding spoilers for this write-up. What I liked most about this movie is the character of Amy played by Rosamund Pike (At World&rsquo;s End). She is not a sociopath ala Lou Bloom in <em>Nightcrawler</em> when she frames her husband Nick (Ben Affleck) for her murder; she feels deeply. And she understands more than anyone in <em>The One I Love</em> about what matters in her marriage. Gillian Flynn (book &amp; screenwriter) and David Fincher have fun walking us through how she takes revenge on the person who stole away her potential. The visuals are the most stylish of Fincher&rsquo;s career yet and Atticus Ross and Trent Reznor (Nine Inch Nails) deliver an anxiety-inducing score. The unreal dramatics that drive this thrilling plot allow Amy and Nick&rsquo;s relationship to be dissected in the small glances, unreliable memories, and hurt feelings that compose a marriage.</p>

<p><img src="http://c.fastcompany.net/multisite_files/fastcompany/poster/2014/10/3036795-poster-p-1-gone-girl-sharp-objects-and-more-details.jpg"></p>

<h3>3 &ndash; Under The Skin</h3>

<p>This is ostensibly the year of Scarlett Johansson (<em>Lucy</em>, <em>Captain America 2</em>), whose acting talent is so often overshadowed by her sex appeal. Few actors of her status would go full-frontal for a relatively unknown director (Jonathon Glazer) on a movie that is part hidden camera reality show. We are thrown into the car of another nameless Driver, who scours the Scottish backroads picking up men, who are only later informed that it was only for the purposes of a movie. Devastating. The scenes depicting an alien adjust to life in a European town are incredibly poignant. The visual palette that Glazer uses is uniquely beautiful. This is a movie that you go see by yourself, that affixes you to the screen in awe.</p>

<p><img src="http://d1oi7t5trwfj5d.cloudfront.net/94/dc/837548e74bb8a722183beb291731/under-the-skin.jpg"></p>

<h3>2 &ndash; The Grand Budapest Hotel</h3>

<p>Who would have thought that the sweetest relationship on screen all year would be between a man and his lobby boy. Wes Anderson&rsquo;s newest paints a beautiful portrait, and I&rsquo;m not talking about Boy with Apple, of Zero Moustafa recounting his mentorship under the legendary concierge M. Gustave (Ralph Fiennes) at the eponymous hotel. If only we were all as lucky to have known this tremendous character. Absolutely loyal, insanely exacting, and completely self-aware.</p>

<blockquote><p>Mr. Moustafa: There are still faint glimmers of civilization left in this barbaric slaughterhouse that was once known as humanity&hellip; He was one of them. What more is there to say?</p></blockquote>

<p><img src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1412046/thumbs/o-GRAND-BUDAPEST-HOTEL-TRAILER-facebook.jpg"></p>

<h3>1 &ndash; Boyhood</h3>

<blockquote><p>Mr.Turlington: Any dipshit can take pictures, Mason. Art, that&rsquo;s special. What can you bring to it that nobody else can?</p></blockquote>

<p>And that&rsquo;s what Richard Linklater does more consistently than any other filmmaker today. He brings it. Following actors growing up in real time is a unique achievement, but that&rsquo;s only half the picture. After all, Linklater did something similar with the Before Sunrise trilogy, filming Ethan Hawke and Julie Delpy every 9 years. What elevates this movie to GOAT status is how effectively the real-time growth of the actors subtly shifted our perspective on the profound and the mundane moments of growing up. To reminisce on those early years is such sweet sorrow. And if all you girls are feeling left out, Linklater&rsquo;s own daughter plays Mason&rsquo;s sister Samantha, who this movie could easily have been about.</p>

<p>-I.I.</p>

<p><img src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-lcPMfZeV05I/VBQ2LouSSSI/AAAAAAAAgfA/xG75eQf4PEo/s1600/Boyhood%2B(Momentos%2Bde%2Buna%2Bvida)%2B-%2B%2BEllar%2BColtrane%2B(Mason)%2Bfinal.jpg"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie Review: Lola Versus]]></title>
    <link href="http://four-point-play.herokuapp.com/blog/2014/05/06/movie-review-lola-versus/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-06T19:06:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://four-point-play.herokuapp.com/blog/2014/05/06/movie-review-lola-versus</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/Lola_Versus.jpg" title="Lola Versus" alt="alt text" /></p>

<p>Director: Daryl Wein<br/>
Runtime: 87 minutes<br/>
Cast: Greta Gerwig, Hamish Linklater, Zoe Lister-Jones<br/></p>

<!--more-->


<p>This hidden gem has been lying on my coffee table for two months after I picked it up for under five bucks at my local video store. It was part of a double feature purchase which also included Evil Dead, to be reviewed shortly. The sole reason it caught my eye was because of Ms. Gerwig’s mesmerizing performance as <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Frances_Ha">Frances Ha</a>’s titular heroine in one of the best movies of 2012. Director and co-writer Noah Baumbach left his wife and child during this collaboration, so it’s not just me that is caught in her magnetic field. And she will go on to reboot the How I Met Your Mother franchise by drudging through the story of HSMHH in HIMYD. HIMYM is one of my favorite sitcoms,  dare I say the Friends of my generation, and it has been endlessly renewed past its expiration date. Part of the reason, I presume, the finale felt so foreign to many viewers. My opinion, I loved how they ended things. But, it does a lot to sooth my anxieites that this spinoff will be anchored by this capable, indie star.</p>

<p>Before all her recent success, this film showcased her remarkable talent. It centers around the year between her 29th and 30th birthday, no small time in anyone’s life. She is joined in NYC by romantic interest Luke (Joel Kinnaman), best friend Alice (Zoe Lister Jones), and male-best-friend-who-obviously-has-a-crush-on-her Henry (Hamish Linklater!). You&rsquo;ve watched enough romantic comedies to know where this is going. She ends up with the more compatible best friend after making a few mistakes along the way. The writers refreshingly barrel through plot points to arrive at that ending halfway through the movie. This would not have worked without the splendid ability of these actors to develop a quick, believable chemistry. The relationships are strained mainly due to the reluctance of these characters to communicate, all coming to culmination in a nervous breakdown. The strength of this film comes on the comedic half of its pursuits. The dialogue is clever and fresh, helped tremendously by the delivery of Gerwig and crew. Pay attention to the set pieces too, if you&rsquo;ve ever wondered what a happenstance prison architect has on his walls. If you like to complain about how Hollywood can&rsquo;t make a comedic film with female leads, check this one out.</p>

<p>While we get some fun situations in the story of Lola dealing with the stresses of her romantic life, I am left wondering why she constantly befuddles her own attempts at growth. It seems to be assumed that this how women her age in this culture deal with life. Her stagnation turns quickly into frustration for the viewer who has learned the lessons that romantic comedies have to teach us. &ldquo;You’re making all the classic mistakes!&rdquo;, you want to yell at the hapless girl. Her parents' sage advice is the proxy for the omniscient viewer, which Lola promptly ignores in the scenes after they disappear. As she showed in the far superior, Frances Ha, which revolves around the same topics, one can mine the depths of the relationships between friends and lovers, while still being funny. I am scared that CBS execs saw this movie and thought that we could get Greta Gerwig easily drag out her romantic growth through 9 seasons as she did through this hour-and-a-half movie. It is a waste of her talent, but good exploitation of her appeal.</p>

<blockquote><p>“Whatever, chicks love old phones. They think I listen more or something.”</p></blockquote>

<p>-I.I.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
