<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Basketball | Four-Point Play]]></title>
  <link href="http://four-point-play.herokuapp.com/blog/categories/basketball/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://four-point-play.herokuapp.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-04-28T11:45:03-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://four-point-play.herokuapp.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Logesh and Geoff]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[2015 NBA Playoff Predictions]]></title>
    <link href="http://four-point-play.herokuapp.com/blog/2015/04/17/2015-nba-playoff-predictions/"/>
    <updated>2015-04-17T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://four-point-play.herokuapp.com/blog/2015/04/17/2015-nba-playoff-predictions</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Logesh and Geoff&rsquo;s ridiculously <s>uninformed</s> <b>bold</b> NBA playoff finals predictions:</p>

<p><img src="http://hardwoodparoxysm.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/6/2014/06/kevin-love-lebron-james-nba-minnesota-timberwolves-miami-heat.jpg" /></p>

<!--more-->




<h2 class="text-center">Conference First Round</h2>


<h3>West</h3>


<table class="table table-striped">
  <tr>
    <th></th>
    <th>Logesh</th>
    <th>Geoff</th>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td>1 Golden State vs. 8 New Orleans</td>
    <td>Golden State in 5</td>
    <td>Golden State in 5</td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td>4 Portland vs. 5 Memphis</td>
    <td>Memphis in 6</td>
    <td>Memphis in 5</td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td>3 LA Clippers vs. 6 San Antonio</td>
    <td>San Antonio in 6</td>
    <td>LA Clippers in 6</td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td>2 Houston vs. 7 Dallas</td>
    <td>Houston in 5</td>
    <td>Houston in 6</td>
  </tr>
</table>




<h3>East</h3>


<table class="table table-striped">
  <tr>
    <td></td>
    <td>Logesh</td>
    <td>Geoff</td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td>1 Atlanta vs. 8 Brooklyn</td>
    <td>Atlanta in 4</td>
    <td>Atlanta in 5</td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td>4 Toronto vs. 5 Washinton</td>
    <td>Toronto in 6</td>
    <td>Toronto in 7</td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td>3 Chicago vs. 6 Milwaukee</td>
    <td>Chicago in 5</td>
    <td>Chicago in 6</td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td>2 Cleveland vs. 7 Boston</td>
    <td>Cleveland in 6</td>
    <td>Cleveland in 4</td>
  </tr>
</table>




<h2 class="text-center">Conference Semifinals</h2>


<h3>West</h3>


<table class="table table-striped">
  <tr>
    <th>Logesh</th>
    <th>Geoff</th>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td>Golden State over Memphis in 6</td>
    <td>Memphis over Golden State in 6</td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td>San Antonio over Houston in 7</td>
    <td>LA Clippers over Houston in 7</td>
  </tr>
</table>




<h3>East</h3>


<table class="table table-striped">
  <tr>
    <th>Logesh</th>
    <th>Geoff</th>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td>Atlanta over Toronto in 6</td>
    <td>Atlanta over Toronto in 6</td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td>Chicago over Cleveland in 7</td>
    <td>Cleveland over Chicago in 6</td>
  </tr>
</table>




<h2 class="text-center">Conference Finals</h2>


<h3>West</h3>


<table class="table table-striped">
  <tr>
    <th>Logesh</th>
    <th>Geoff</th>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td>Golden State over San Antonio in 6</td>
    <td>LA Clippers over Memphis in 7</td>
  </tr>
</table>




<h3>East</h3>


<table class="table table-striped">
  <tr>
    <th>Logesh</th>
    <th>Geoff</th>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td>Atlanta over Chicago in 6</td>
    <td>Cleveland over Atlanta in 7</td>
  </tr>
</table>




<h2 class="text-center">NBA Finals</h2>


<table class="table table-striped">
  <tr>
    <th>Logesh</th>
    <th>Geoff</th>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td>Golden State over Atlanta in 7</td>
    <td>Cleveland over LA Clippers in 6</td>
  </tr>
</table>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Logesh and Geoff's NBA Preview 2014-15]]></title>
    <link href="http://four-point-play.herokuapp.com/blog/2014/11/19/nba-preview/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-19T18:20:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://four-point-play.herokuapp.com/blog/2014/11/19/nba-preview</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s Logesh and Geoff&rsquo;s (belated) NBA Preview for 2014-15!</p>

<hr />


<p><img src="http://www.sportsgrid.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/Cleveland-Cavaliers-vs.-Miami-Heat-640x360-628x353.jpg" /></p>

<!--more-->




<h2>The East</h2>




<p>1. Bulls (60-22) – I BELIEVE THAT WE WILL WIN. Rose’s Team USA performance induced a mild panic, as will every time he hits the floor. But in the preseason, we saw him shake off the rust and produce glimmers of his trademark explosiveness. But this team is not all about our returning PG. Pau Gasol is a solid upgrade on both defense and offense from Boozer to our starting 5. Though it will take time to find a place for him in the post with Noah and Gibson. And speaking of Taj, he will win sixth man this year, after being robbed last season. The concerns about scoring were addressed by bringing Mirotic over from Real Madrid and drafting Dougy McBuckets (aka Doug McDermott), the NCAA leader in scoring last year, and Kyle Korver 2.0 (both from Creighton!). The most important piece of this puzzle is Thibs. With possibly his best Bulls roster yet, he’ll be as irascible and demanding as ever on his way to the top of the Eastern conference.</p>




<p>2.  Cleveland Cavaliers (52-30)  - I’m heavily biased, but I do think there is this big of a gap between the Bulls and the rest of the Eastern Conference. The new Big 3 are going to need time to build chemistry. But in the dreadful eastern conference, they’ll get that chance by beating on less talented rosters. Outside of Love, Irving, and Bron-bron, the talent level drops significantly. At shooting guard are perennial sixth man Dion Waiters and Mike Miller, hardly inspiring. Varejao and Tristan Thompson at center are decent players, but they are a far cry from the Eastern Conference corps of elite centers - Noah, Bosh, pre-breakdown Hibbert, and Lopez. A lackluster bench and supporting crew are not a recipe for multiple championships... just look at the Spurs.</p>




<p>3.  Washington Wizards (49 – 33) – I had a hard time hating these guys when they outplayed my Bulls in the playoffs. Big men Nenê and Gortat play hard ball and will not let up easy points. Overall #1 pick John Wall is starting to play like it, leading the league in assists last year. I like these guys!</p>




<p>4.  Brooklyn Nets (45 - 37) – Don’t forget these ballers swept the Heat in the regular season last year. They had a rocky start til the All-Star break. Joe Johnson is a force on their offense, making Atlanta fan’s rue the day they traded him. But their old and might have hit their peak already.</p>




<p>5.  Toronto Raptors (44 - 38) – DeMar DeRozan blew up on the Raptors last year, averaging 22.7 points with a handful of rebounds and assists.  And let’s not forget Drake is dropping a new album this year. <a href="http://youtu.be/6IdmyC6WnXI" target="_blank">Just keep him off the court</a>.</p>




<p>6.  New York Knicks  (43 - 41) – Jackson and Fisher’s triangle offense will be the story surrounding this team. With Stoudemire back at 100%, playing the low post in this scheme, his talent could finally be realized on the Knicks. Calderon is an underrated point guard, and along with Iman Shumpert, I have no doubt they will effectively run the offense.</p>




<p>7.  Miami Heat (38 – 46) – Wade, Bosh, and Deng are no small threat. Hopefully, Spoelstra will finally get the credit he deserves as a coach, when he takes a James-less team to the playoffs. Oh and they’ll be playing Lebron in the playoffs. Probably take the Cavs to a Game 7, before bowing out gracefully. This is just the kind of shit that happens to the King.</p>




<p>8.  Charlotte ~~Bobcats~~ Hornets (36 – 48) – These guys added Lance Stephenson in the offseason, with MJ granting free reign to his <a href="(http://youtu.be/Cz3wvCNnF98" target="_blank">weird-ass behavior</a>. They’ve got a core group of young guys in Kemba Walker, Michael Kidd-Gilchrist, and Cody Zeller that will only keep getting better. Veteran Al Jefferson is back from plantar fasciitis, that hellish irritation, and will be holding down the defense.</p>




<p>9. Atlanta Hawks (33 – 51) - Perennially in the barely made/missed the playoffs spot.</p>




<p>10. Boston Celtics (31—53) – As long as Rondo doesn’t get traded mid-season.</p>




<p>11. Detroit Pistons (29 – 51)</p>




<p>12. Indiana Pacers (27 – 53) - Pour one out for Paul George.</p>




<p>13. Orlando Magic (23 – 59)</p>




<p>14. Milwaukee Bucks (20 – 62)</p>




<p>15. Philadelphia 76ers (17 – 65) - Tank City</p>




<hr/>




<h2>The West</h2>


<p><img src="http://cdn.fansided.com/wp-content/blogs.dir/246/files/2013/11/7827526.jpg" /></p>

<p>1.  San Antonio (58 - 24) - What's left to say about this team, this franchise, this coach, and his key pieces? They play team ball better than most. They'll win what's theirs. Let's see what's in the tank come the playoffs.</p>




<p>1.  Golden State (58 - 24) - David Lee is an underrated star. Though I'd like to think otherwise, Klay Thompson's max contract is ludicrous. He would have taken the hometown discount, right? If this team is going to win, it has to win now. That's why I think the Lee-Thompson-Currey does just that: wins now. I see no issue with the Warriors taking over the OKC slot and wrapping the season in the 2nd or 3rd seed.</p>




<p>3.  Houston (50 - 32) - Unlike other American sports leagues, in the NBA there's a concept called "winning the offseason". Every, single, offseason. The LeBron / Melo / Love / Garnett / whomever "sweepstakes". This offseason, we had Bosh courting suitors. And while the Cavs dominated the offseason, the Rockets pulled a diametric opposite. No LeBron, and then when Bosh was in their sights... no Bosh. That said, they still have two of the top ten players in the league, including arguably the best, most diva-licious center around (sorry, Joakim). I like them in the regular season. We'll see how they fare otherwise.</p>




<p>4.  Memphis (49 - 33)</p>




<p>5.  LA Clippers (47 - 35) - Quite the divisive team. Some folks think they hit a peak last year; some folks think they're just getting started. You're not gonna like this Logesh, but I tend to side with the former.</p>




<p>6.  Portland (46 - 36) - Rising superpower might be an overstatement, but there's no lack of power on this team. I really like Lopez (the quiet, non-Net one) last year, posting some of his best numbers of his career. Plus, who doesn't like Lillard's upside? He's a point guard that doesn't take over a game, but doesn't mean he couldn't. He'll post 7 APG and 20 PPG.</p>




<p>7.  Dallas (44 - 38)</p>




<p>7.  Oklahoma City (44 - 38) - Oh boy. Hindsight is 50-50, my friend, and at this rate, might be their win-loss percentage. Their schedule is inherently brutal, and now they're missing their two key pieces. The identity of the team is shattered. Do they make the playoffs? I'll give them an edge. I like Ibaka, and feel like their set piece players are enough to hold them over against the nadir of the Western conference (read: several Timberwolves and Lakers games).  Where they go from there is up to the team doctors.</p>




<p>9.  Phoenix (42 - 40)</p>




<p>10.  New Orleans (41 - 41) - Time for the 'Brow to take over... at least half their games.</p>




<p>11.  Denver (37 - 45) - It hurts me to write about this team, who two years ago had the coach of the year and several fantastic players. I witnessed Iguodala hit a game-winner live against the high-flying Thunder. But now he's a Warrior, and only Faried gives me hope.</p>




<p>12.  Sacramento (28 - 54) - Bleh.</p>




<p>13.  Minnesota (27 - 55) - No comment.</p>




<p>14.  Utah (20 - 62)</p>




<p>15.  LA Lakers (0 - 82) - alrightfineI'mkidding. But do they have anyone on their team that plays defense? No. A 36-year-old off-an-injury Kobe is still technically a Kobe, but the Lakers are in full rebuilding mode. And last night he hit a career low with a bazillion missed shots. He can't carry this team. Let's hope they can cash in that lottery ticket. </p>




<hr />


<p>Happy Hoops Season,</p>

<ul>
<li>GPS &amp; I.I.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Pathetic Pacers]]></title>
    <link href="http://four-point-play.herokuapp.com/blog/2014/05/29/the-pathetic-pacers/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-29T17:05:49-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://four-point-play.herokuapp.com/blog/2014/05/29/the-pathetic-pacers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/lance.png" title="Lance Acting a Clown" alt="alt text" /></p>

<p>Herein lies my quick thoughts on the pathetic Indiana Pacers team, and why I need them to lose game 6 to enjoy watching the rest of the playoffs.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>I grew up without much of a sporting interest in basketball, let alone a rooting interest in my home-town Nets and Knicks; ergo, my passion for the sport extends to a love of most teams, and a general appreciation for fundamental, tough, skilled basketball.</p>

<p>In short: I want the clown car that drops the Pacers team off at American Airlines arena tomorrow to blow a tire and go careening off into South Beach. I need this bush-league playoff run to end.</p>

<p>I wanted it to end against the Hawks. I expected it to end against the Wizards. And now I <strong>need</strong> it to end against the Heat. Here&rsquo;s why.</p>

<p><b>The driver of the clown car: Frank Vogel.</b> It&rsquo;s hard to watch, frankly. This is what I mean by pathetic &ndash; pathos. I feel bad for the guy. He&rsquo;s in way over his head, and is barely keeping the show on the road. When George, Hibbert, and Stephenson talk to the media or fall apart on the court, it&rsquo;s clearly a reflection on the coach, his style, and the respect he commands.</p>

<p><b>Paul George&rsquo;s immaturity.</b> His 31 in the second half of game 5 was great. Does anyone expect him to repeat that? He&rsquo;s been hailed as a superstar this year. He&rsquo;s not. He&rsquo;s been hailed as their centerpiece, but he hardly brings the playoff room together. And his childish comments that the &ldquo;refs affected game 4&rsquo;s outcome&rdquo;? Did the refs blow you out by 12 points in a game that was never even that close? No. That was the Heat.</p>

<p><b>Lance Stephenson&rsquo;s trash talk.</b> Really? You&rsquo;re going to sit there as the &ldquo;occasionally 3rd best player&rdquo; on a team and try to get in the best player <b>in the league&rsquo;s</b> head? Two losses later I thought he&rsquo;d back down. But no: in game 5 he <b>blew in James' ear before a foul shot</b> and then <b>tried to listen in on a Heat huddle</b>. I know some basketball players didn&rsquo;t go to college, but surely y'all have graduated middle school, the very <b>last</b> time that stunt was socially acceptable. At least you&rsquo;ve inspired some great <a href="http://espn.go.com/sportsnation/post/_/id/11001550/lance-stephenson-blows-lebron-ear-sparks-funny-memes">memes</a>, Lance.</p>

<p>In short: finish &lsquo;em off, Heat. The first-seed Pacers are barely the sixth seed in Western Conference. Their brash childishness must be stopped. I&rsquo;d hate to watch a Pacers-versus <b>anyone</b> final. If they&rsquo;re going to act petulant, play out-of-their-league, and frankly be painful-to-watch, count me out. That&rsquo;s just the basketball fan in me.</p>

<ul>
<li>GPS</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[2014 NBA Conference Finals - Part 1]]></title>
    <link href="http://four-point-play.herokuapp.com/blog/2014/05/20/2014-nba-conference-finals-part-1/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-20T16:50:54-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://four-point-play.herokuapp.com/blog/2014/05/20/2014-nba-conference-finals-part-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Part 1 in I.I. and GPS&rsquo;s series on the NBA Conference Finals. We talk about whether the Heat should worry, Scotty Brook&rsquo;s tough decision, and Charles Barkley actin' a fool.</p>

<!--more-->


<p><strong>I.I.</strong>: The match-ups are set! On both sides the top two seeds are squaring off. A bipolar Pacers team stumbled to the conference finals against the Eastern conference favorite Heat. The MVP-led Thunder, minus Serge Ibaka, will take on Popovich&rsquo;s Spurs. So GeoSpec, what are your thoughts?</p>

<p>Will the Thunder&rsquo;s young guns wear out a veteran Spurs team that closed out the series against Portland with their bench? Will the Pacers surprise us by taking a couple games on the road against the Heat, as they are apt to do? And what about the big &lsquo;ol woman down in San Antonio? Will they come to some sort of truce with Charles Barkley?</p>

<p><strong>GPS</strong>: These are the match ups everyone wanted, right? A rematch of last year&rsquo;s Eastern Conference Finals, and a likely (sorry, Pacers) rematch of either the 2012 or 2013 NBA finals upcoming. Let&rsquo;s break it down. We&rsquo;ll pose some questions, we&rsquo;ll both give our take. Boom:</p>

<h4>Should the Heat be worried after dropping game 1 to the inconsistent Pacers?</h4>


<p><strong>GPS</strong>: I hate to say it: yes. But maybe not for the reasons you&rsquo;d think. It&rsquo;s really more about the Heat than the Pacers. The Heat have been coasting on production from LeBron and an occasional set piece (mostly Allen) for two series now. Where has Bosh been? Will the Heat&rsquo;s lack of size pose another problem? What about that game 7 home court advantage? Can they get another 81% shooting rampage from someone like Chris Andersen (2013)? These are all concerns. The Heat can win on the road. They have this year, and did last year against these same Pacers. But they&rsquo;re concerns regardless. The Pacers have been shaky, sure, and I still can&rsquo;t see them winning the series; but for whatever reason, the Pacers play significantly harder against the Heat.</p>

<p><strong>I.I.</strong>: You know, you&rsquo;re the second person today to tell me they can see the schizophrenic Pacers winning this series. If they end up in the Finals, I envision a sweep at the hands of the Spurs. The only entertaining part of that series would be Popovich coaching against his former protégé George Hill. The Pacers won 3 of their 4 against the Wizards on the road. Without much home court advantage on either side, I can see this series alternating until a Heat blowout in Game 7 at Indiana. Indiana&rsquo;s got size, but if Bosh and Chalmers start to pick it up, and Battier and Allen sink clutch 3s like they&rsquo;re paid to do, it will be hard for Paul George &amp; crew to keep up.</p>

<h4>What do you make of the Spurs shutting down the Thunder in Game 1?</h4>


<p><strong>I.I.</strong>: I don&rsquo;t envy the decisions Scotty Brooks has to make right now. I would hedge my bets on the side of sticking to small ball to match the firepower of the Spurs, which was how they overcame the Clippers. It was inexcusable for 2 OKC starters to put up goose eggs, and that&rsquo;s certainly going to change. But they miss Ibaka&rsquo;s offense because the smaller Reggie Jackson and Caron Butler are clearly overmatched against the defense of Splitter and Diaw.  Going big would require Durant and Westbrook to carry the offense, which, if the emotions are there, they do for two games tops.  The Thunder are not out of this by a long shot, having lost their last four road Game 1s, but it&rsquo;s not good to be lucky that you were only down 8 at the half. Also, the Spurs a whopping +30 with Danny Green on the floor, whaaaat.</p>

<p><strong>GPS</strong>: The Thunder might be missing Ibaka already. Any Spur could get to the rim at will in game 1. I can only imagine that continuing in game 2. The Spurs outscored the Thunder 66 to 32 in the paint. I couldn&rsquo;t believe that stat when I saw it.  Clearly playing small backfired for Scott Brooks. They&rsquo;ll have to get someone to replace Ibaka, or this series could turn ugly.</p>

<h4>Who do you have in Game 2 of each series?</h4>


<p><strong>GPS</strong>: Heat. I just don&rsquo;t believe the Pacers can win two in a row. They couldn&rsquo;t against the Hawks. They won&rsquo;t against the Heat. They&rsquo;re 4 and 4 at home this season, and can&rsquo;t imagine the Heat allowing 30 in another first quarter, as they did in a miserable game 1 showing.</p>

<p><strong>I.I.</strong>: Heat, with Bosh having a monster game and Lance Stephenson going 2 for 10. I&rsquo;m thinking the Spurs are gonna put another beatdown on OKC. I think the Thunder&rsquo;s coaching staff needs another game to figure out what to do against these guys. Maybe pull in some of those big ol' women down in San Antonio to crowd the paint.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
