<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Medical School | Four-Point Play]]></title>
  <link href="http://four-point-play.herokuapp.com/blog/categories/medical-school/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://four-point-play.herokuapp.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-09-23T20:01:02-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://four-point-play.herokuapp.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Logesh and Geoff]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Professionalism in Medicine]]></title>
    <link href="http://four-point-play.herokuapp.com/blog/2014/05/15/professionalism-in-medicine/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-15T13:39:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://four-point-play.herokuapp.com/blog/2014/05/15/professionalism-in-medicine</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We are comporting ourselves in every situation, subconsciously considering our role, our expectations, the other parties’ expectations, and our prior experiences. In this coffee shop, I am a customer expecting quiet, because that is the unspoken pact I share with the afternoon crowd that frequents this place. I distinctly remember a philosophy course when I brought up how we are different people to different people, and a Laker purple-and-gold clad loudmouth was taken aback. She seemed to argue that it demonstrated purity to be the same to all people all the time. Maybe it is because we slip so effortlessly into these skins, that some people are unaware. A refusal to acknowledge this socially lubricating farce could underpin those stubborn people who can’t seem to get along with anyone. An inability to adapt can be a stressful way to live.</p>

<p><img src="/images/comic1.jpg" title="Lola Versus" alt="alt text" /></p>

<!--more-->


<p>Many of our &ldquo;professional&rdquo; lives are a journey into learning the rules of how to behave in our workplace environs. How should I dress? What are the right things to do to make the boss see that I’m valuable? Should I be networking more? Some people find mentors whose habits they mimic to fit in better. It is an organic process, of how an individual integrates into a group.</p>

<p>So, professionalism is the attributes ascribed to a profession. It is gained as one transitions from being an amateur to going pro.  As a medical student about to enter his fourth and final year, at the conclusion of which people will start calling him and considering him “doctor”, it is of utmost concern.</p>

<p><img src="/images/comic2.gif" title="Lola Versus" alt="alt text" /></p>

<p>At the top of our end-of-rotation evaluations, the preceptor is asked if the student exhibited professionalism. If the answer is no, nothing else matters, you’re retaking the rotation. And so daily, we student doctors fret over how we can best exude professionalism. The syllabus requires wearing a tie for males. But, save for the occasional hospital administrator/CEO, the med student is the best dressed person in a hospital of assumedly unprofessional slobs. Short white coats must be worn at all times. Aside from this being inexcusable as a proven infection-transmitting nidus, it doesn’t even convey your role anymore. Everyone from the social worker to the pharmacist now rocks the off-white coat.</p>

<p>What about learning professionalism from our superiors, the godly attending physicians whose shoes we will one day fill? In this hierarchical profession, they berate us for not being able to read their minds on how they want a patient presented. They knowingly grill us on the minutiae of some piece of medical knowledge, indignant when we fumble the answer. If they don’t treat the lowly students with respect, they surely wouldn’t be so cavalier with their patients. As you&rsquo;ve surely experienced, it is uncommon to be in a room where the doc spends more time looking at the patient than at a computer screen or chart. Unfortunately, an academic single-mindedness can thrive in this field. Empathy and rapport-building skills are never assessed for entry into medical school or residency.</p>

<p>The true essence of professionalism in medicine is the doctor who respects and treats a patient’s medical and psychological concerns. Most docs can process clinical signs, symptoms, and lab data to prescribe the recommended treatment. Magic medicine delivered through an IV does little to assuage the worry that wracks anyone inside the medical system juggernaut.  I did an experiment where I either introduced myself as a medical student or an undergraduate at my school’s health center. You might think that in the former, I received special treatment like a native in an ethnic restaurant. But, the fact mattered little. I felt like little more than an obstacle in their workflow, despite my attempts at forming  a connection by asking about their day, family, etc. I am guilty of this too. My main concern is often to get in and out of a room as quickly as I can so I can write my note and go home early.</p>

<p><img src="/images/comic3.gif" title="Lola Versus" alt="alt text" /></p>

<p>One afternoon, my faculty mentor came by the hospital and showed me how a real pro does it. Unabashedly, he started with non-sequitur icebreakers like it was summer camp, instead of the scripted, remote “What brings you to the hospital/clinic/ER today?” And he pushes for answers.</p>

<blockquote><p>“I dunno…”</p>

<p>“Come on there must be something you like doing in your free time?”</p>

<p>“I guess I really enjoy playing with my 4yo daughter.”</p></blockquote>

<p>Suddenly, a particularly obstinate pain patient wasn’t feeling too bad anymore.</p>

<p>Medical professionalism is the relationship we are able to develop with our patients and our coworkers. It goes beyond making someone else feel warm &amp; fuzzy. In this field, a person’s healthy and vitality, and sometimes life or limb, is on the line. What matters most is being able to trust a patient’s testimony, them reciprocating the trust by allowing us to intervene, and the team trusting each other to get the job done quickly and correctly. While we are assessed by our starched white coats and biohazard neck ties, shouldn&rsquo;t some consideration be given to the professionalism that is demonstrated by treating a patient as more than a disease process? With little emphasis on its teaching, a paucity of mentors, and an overburdened healthcare system, the professional doctor, like the do-it-all family doc, might become a relic of the past.</p>

<ul>
<li>I.I.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
