<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Playoffs | Four-Point Play]]></title>
  <link href="http://four-point-play.herokuapp.com/blog/categories/playoffs/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://four-point-play.herokuapp.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-01-14T09:32:08-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://four-point-play.herokuapp.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Logesh and Geoff]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[2014 NBA Conference Finals - Part 1]]></title>
    <link href="http://four-point-play.herokuapp.com/blog/2014/05/20/2014-nba-conference-finals-part-1/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-20T16:50:54-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://four-point-play.herokuapp.com/blog/2014/05/20/2014-nba-conference-finals-part-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Part 1 in I.I. and GPS&rsquo;s series on the NBA Conference Finals. We talk about whether the Heat should worry, Scotty Brook&rsquo;s tough decision, and Charles Barkley actin' a fool.</p>

<!--more-->


<p><strong>I.I.</strong>: The match-ups are set! On both sides the top two seeds are squaring off. A bipolar Pacers team stumbled to the conference finals against the Eastern conference favorite Heat. The MVP-led Thunder, minus Serge Ibaka, will take on Popovich&rsquo;s Spurs. So GeoSpec, what are your thoughts?</p>

<p>Will the Thunder&rsquo;s young guns wear out a veteran Spurs team that closed out the series against Portland with their bench? Will the Pacers surprise us by taking a couple games on the road against the Heat, as they are apt to do? And what about the big &lsquo;ol woman down in San Antonio? Will they come to some sort of truce with Charles Barkley?</p>

<p><strong>GPS</strong>: These are the match ups everyone wanted, right? A rematch of last year&rsquo;s Eastern Conference Finals, and a likely (sorry, Pacers) rematch of either the 2012 or 2013 NBA finals upcoming. Let&rsquo;s break it down. We&rsquo;ll pose some questions, we&rsquo;ll both give our take. Boom:</p>

<h4>Should the Heat be worried after dropping game 1 to the inconsistent Pacers?</h4>


<p><strong>GPS</strong>: I hate to say it: yes. But maybe not for the reasons you&rsquo;d think. It&rsquo;s really more about the Heat than the Pacers. The Heat have been coasting on production from LeBron and an occasional set piece (mostly Allen) for two series now. Where has Bosh been? Will the Heat&rsquo;s lack of size pose another problem? What about that game 7 home court advantage? Can they get another 81% shooting rampage from someone like Chris Andersen (2013)? These are all concerns. The Heat can win on the road. They have this year, and did last year against these same Pacers. But they&rsquo;re concerns regardless. The Pacers have been shaky, sure, and I still can&rsquo;t see them winning the series; but for whatever reason, the Pacers play significantly harder against the Heat.</p>

<p><strong>I.I.</strong>: You know, you&rsquo;re the second person today to tell me they can see the schizophrenic Pacers winning this series. If they end up in the Finals, I envision a sweep at the hands of the Spurs. The only entertaining part of that series would be Popovich coaching against his former protégé George Hill. The Pacers won 3 of their 4 against the Wizards on the road. Without much home court advantage on either side, I can see this series alternating until a Heat blowout in Game 7 at Indiana. Indiana&rsquo;s got size, but if Bosh and Chalmers start to pick it up, and Battier and Allen sink clutch 3s like they&rsquo;re paid to do, it will be hard for Paul George &amp; crew to keep up.</p>

<h4>What do you make of the Spurs shutting down the Thunder in Game 1?</h4>


<p><strong>I.I.</strong>: I don&rsquo;t envy the decisions Scotty Brooks has to make right now. I would hedge my bets on the side of sticking to small ball to match the firepower of the Spurs, which was how they overcame the Clippers. It was inexcusable for 2 OKC starters to put up goose eggs, and that&rsquo;s certainly going to change. But they miss Ibaka&rsquo;s offense because the smaller Reggie Jackson and Caron Butler are clearly overmatched against the defense of Splitter and Diaw.  Going big would require Durant and Westbrook to carry the offense, which, if the emotions are there, they do for two games tops.  The Thunder are not out of this by a long shot, having lost their last four road Game 1s, but it&rsquo;s not good to be lucky that you were only down 8 at the half. Also, the Spurs a whopping +30 with Danny Green on the floor, whaaaat.</p>

<p><strong>GPS</strong>: The Thunder might be missing Ibaka already. Any Spur could get to the rim at will in game 1. I can only imagine that continuing in game 2. The Spurs outscored the Thunder 66 to 32 in the paint. I couldn&rsquo;t believe that stat when I saw it.  Clearly playing small backfired for Scott Brooks. They&rsquo;ll have to get someone to replace Ibaka, or this series could turn ugly.</p>

<h4>Who do you have in Game 2 of each series?</h4>


<p><strong>GPS</strong>: Heat. I just don&rsquo;t believe the Pacers can win two in a row. They couldn&rsquo;t against the Hawks. They won&rsquo;t against the Heat. They&rsquo;re 4 and 4 at home this season, and can&rsquo;t imagine the Heat allowing 30 in another first quarter, as they did in a miserable game 1 showing.</p>

<p><strong>I.I.</strong>: Heat, with Bosh having a monster game and Lance Stephenson going 2 for 10. I&rsquo;m thinking the Spurs are gonna put another beatdown on OKC. I think the Thunder&rsquo;s coaching staff needs another game to figure out what to do against these guys. Maybe pull in some of those big ol' women down in San Antonio to crowd the paint.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
